<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>python on Martin Jung - Environmental and data scientist</title>
    <link>http://martin-jung.github.io/categories/python/</link>
    <description>Recent content in python on Martin Jung - Environmental and data scientist</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <copyright>Martin Jung 2017-2018 &amp;bull; &lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/&#34;&gt;&lt;i class=&#34;fa fa-cc&#34; aria-hidden=&#34;true&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 26 Feb 2019 22:33:06 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://martin-jung.github.io/categories/python/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>LecoS ported to QGIS3</title>
      <link>http://martin-jung.github.io/post/2019-lecos-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Feb 2019 22:33:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://martin-jung.github.io/post/2019-lecos-update/</guid>
      <description>QGIS remains my go-to default QGIS software and I have contributed some python plugins to it in the past. These include the LecoS plugin, which has been cited 22 times so far and still appears to be widely used by researchers and practitioner alike [I do remember helping out with a workshop in Nairobi quite a while back, where everybody appeared to know the plugin].
  However because of other commitments (writing up my PhD thesis at the moment) I am unable to further develop this neat little piece of software.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Robust correlations with xarray and dask</title>
      <link>http://martin-jung.github.io/post/2018-xarrayregression/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 May 2018 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://martin-jung.github.io/post/2018-xarrayregression/</guid>
      <description>I perform most of my analyses using either R or standalone GDAL tools simply because of their general convenience and ease of use. Standard spatial analysis functions and tools are in my opinion still more readily available in R and most R packages are quite mature and well designed ( but see the readme ). Nevertheless python has caught up and a number of really helpful python modules for spatial analyses have been released to this date.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>