<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>phd on Martin Jung - Environmental and data scientist</title>
    <link>http://martin-jung.github.io/categories/phd/</link>
    <description>Recent content in phd on Martin Jung - Environmental and data scientist</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <copyright>Martin Jung 2017-2019 &amp;bull; &lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/&#34;&gt;&lt;i class=&#34;fa fa-cc&#34; aria-hidden=&#34;true&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 17 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://martin-jung.github.io/categories/phd/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>LateX template for Sussex PhD theses</title>
      <link>http://martin-jung.github.io/post/2019-latex-template/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://martin-jung.github.io/post/2019-latex-template/</guid>
      <description>This is a rather short post informing anyone who might read this post and is likely a Sussex PhD student (and presumably found this blog via google, hello google bot :-) ), that I created an unofficial template for Sussex PhD students. I ensured that the template is formatted as required by the Sussex doctoral school, however the template is provided as is and I am not liable for any errors or damages caused by using this template (see license in repository).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Testing multilevel Bayesian models with ordered categorical predictors</title>
      <link>http://martin-jung.github.io/post/2018_bayesianmodelsmonoticpredictors/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://martin-jung.github.io/post/2018_bayesianmodelsmonoticpredictors/</guid>
      <description>Why argue for Bayesian models? Most researchers and data scientists have specific - domain - knowledge about the subject they analyse data for. In a Bayesian analysis framework this knowledge can be refereed to as Prior and the effect und uncertainty surrounding this. Most standard analytical tools do not account for this information. In fact every statistical tool makes some kind of assumptions about your data. Computers do not now per se how your data looks or what limits it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New PhD paper - Pairwise differences in photosynthetic activity</title>
      <link>http://martin-jung.github.io/post/2018_newphdpublication/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://martin-jung.github.io/post/2018_newphdpublication/</guid>
      <description>I can now happily announce that the first chapter of my PhD has been accepted and is going to be published in the Journal Ecography. In this piece I investigated whether pairwise compositional differences between species assemblages (so in the identity and amount of species found in a given place and time) can be explained by a dissimilarity in remotely-sensed vegetation index. I furthermore found that past dissimilarities in photosynthetic activity improved the overall fit relative to current dissimilarities, therefore hinting at a lag-effect that can be investigated via remote sensing.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>