<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Martin Jung - Environmental and data scientist</title>
    <link>http://martin-jung.github.io/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Martin Jung - Environmental and data scientist</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <copyright>Martin Jung 2017-2018 &amp;bull; &lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/&#34;&gt;&lt;i class=&#34;fa fa-cc&#34; aria-hidden=&#34;true&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://martin-jung.github.io/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>LecoS ported to QGIS3</title>
      <link>http://martin-jung.github.io/post/2019-lecos-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Feb 2019 22:33:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://martin-jung.github.io/post/2019-lecos-update/</guid>
      <description>QGIS remains my go-to default QGIS software and I have contributed some python plugins to it in the past. These include the LecoS plugin, which has been cited 22 times so far and still appears to be widely used by researchers and practitioner alike [I do remember helping out with a workshop in Nairobi quite a while back, where everybody appeared to know the plugin].
  However because of other commitments (writing up my PhD thesis at the moment) I am unable to further develop this neat little piece of software.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LateX template for Sussex PhD theses</title>
      <link>http://martin-jung.github.io/post/2019-latex-template/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://martin-jung.github.io/post/2019-latex-template/</guid>
      <description>This is a rather short post informing anyone who might read this post and is likely a Sussex PhD student (and presumably found this blog via google, hello google bot :-) ), that I created an unofficial template for Sussex PhD students. I ensured that the template is formatted as required by the Sussex doctoral school, however the template is provided as is and I am not liable for any errors or damages caused by using this template (see license in repository).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using the GPU for gradient descent boosting</title>
      <link>http://martin-jung.github.io/post/2018_xgbboostcuda/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://martin-jung.github.io/post/2018_xgbboostcuda/</guid>
      <description>Running machine learning algorithms on large amounts of data can take considerable time. There are multiple ways of speeding up your code. The most obvious is to properly parallize your code and/or - assuming R or python is used - replace certain functions that cause a bottleneck to faster languages such as C++ or Julia. What also works is to simply have more computational power. In a previous post I elaborated on how to make use of the google cloud processing platform.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Testing multilevel Bayesian models with ordered categorical predictors</title>
      <link>http://martin-jung.github.io/post/2018_bayesianmodelsmonoticpredictors/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://martin-jung.github.io/post/2018_bayesianmodelsmonoticpredictors/</guid>
      <description>Why argue for Bayesian models? Most researchers and data scientists have specific - domain - knowledge about the subject they analyse data for. In a Bayesian analysis framework this knowledge can be refereed to as Prior and the effect und uncertainty surrounding this. Most standard analytical tools do not account for this information. In fact every statistical tool makes some kind of assumptions about your data. Computers do not now per se how your data looks or what limits it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New PhD paper - Pairwise differences in photosynthetic activity</title>
      <link>http://martin-jung.github.io/post/2018_newphdpublication/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://martin-jung.github.io/post/2018_newphdpublication/</guid>
      <description>I can now happily announce that the first chapter of my PhD has been accepted and is going to be published in the Journal Ecography. In this piece I investigated whether pairwise compositional differences between species assemblages (so in the identity and amount of species found in a given place and time) can be explained by a dissimilarity in remotely-sensed vegetation index. I furthermore found that past dissimilarities in photosynthetic activity improved the overall fit relative to current dissimilarities, therefore hinting at a lag-effect that can be investigated via remote sensing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Running rstudio in the Google cloud - [2]</title>
      <link>http://martin-jung.github.io/post/2018_datascienceingooglecloud_nr2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://martin-jung.github.io/post/2018_datascienceingooglecloud_nr2/</guid>
      <description>In this new post I will go through my process of getting familiar with running R in the Google cloud and the posting sort of follows my previous post on getting started with the Google cloud. My dream setup would include to being able to switch seamless between running r code locally or in the cloud whenever I require more processing power. For instance similar doAzureParallel package available for Microsoft Azure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to Google Earth Engine</title>
      <link>http://martin-jung.github.io/post/2018_googleearthengine-intro/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://martin-jung.github.io/post/2018_googleearthengine-intro/</guid>
      <description>In a previous post, I gave a brief introduction how to use google cloud compute to kickstart your cloud computing experience. While it is possible to run large spatial operations on google cloud compute, it is quite time-consuming to set up all the routines to load and process geospatial data. Luckily there is now a new platform (currently in beta-testing) called Google Earth Engine (GEE) described as planetary scale platform for spatial analyses.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PhD research image prize</title>
      <link>http://martin-jung.github.io/post/2018-phd-poster-prize/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://martin-jung.github.io/post/2018-phd-poster-prize/</guid>
      <description>I won a prize :-) In this years Festival of Doctoral research at the University of Sussex I won the runner-up prize for the best image describing one&amp;rsquo;s doctoral research. The task was to submit a single image and 300 word abstract that visualizes and describes the goals of a persons doctoral research.
Picture seen above (click here for larger version). Here is the accompanying description:
Title: Going back in time with satellites to assist biodiversity conservation  In my PhD I investigate how past land changes continue to affect local biodiversity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data science in the Google cloud - [1]</title>
      <link>http://martin-jung.github.io/post/2018_datascienceingooglecloud/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://martin-jung.github.io/post/2018_datascienceingooglecloud/</guid>
      <description>Anyone analysing big data (buzzword, here refereed to as data too big to load into memory) soon will come to the realization that processing such data requires a lot of computational resources. During my PhD I mainly worked with the local high-performance-computer (HPC) at the University of Sussex. A couple of years into my PhD and I increasingly realized that our little HPC suffers from the tragedy of the commons with more and more people requesting computation time on a few available nodes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Robust correlations with xarray and dask</title>
      <link>http://martin-jung.github.io/post/2018-xarrayregression/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 May 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://martin-jung.github.io/post/2018-xarrayregression/</guid>
      <description>I perform most of my analyses using either R or standalone GDAL tools simply because of their general convenience and ease of use. Standard spatial analysis functions and tools are in my opinion still more readily available in R and most R packages are quite mature and well designed ( but see the readme ). Nevertheless python has caught up and a number of really helpful python modules for spatial analyses have been released to this date.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New professional website</title>
      <link>http://martin-jung.github.io/post/2017-new-professional-website/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://martin-jung.github.io/post/2017-new-professional-website/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to my new starting website. My name is Martin Jung and I consider myself an Environmental and data scientist. Read here for more.
I have abandoned my previous online presence, the Conservation ecology blog since quite a while. Mostly because I was too preoccupied working on my PhD. However I also disliked the inflexibility of wordpress layouts and the added advertising below each wordpress.com article. Therefore the restart of my professional website powered by hugo and the academic theme.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>