<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>biodiversity | Martin Jung</title>
    <link>https://martinjung.eu/tag/biodiversity/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://martinjung.eu/tag/biodiversity/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>biodiversity</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-gb</language><copyright>© 2021 Martin Jung </copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 03 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://martinjung.eu/media/logo_hu08891b619dca7ea3a10c5ed6def994ae_9949_300x300_fit_lanczos_2.png</url>
      <title>biodiversity</title>
      <link>https://martinjung.eu/tag/biodiversity/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>New PhD paper - Pairwise differences in photosynthetic activity</title>
      <link>https://martinjung.eu/post/2018_newphdpublication/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://martinjung.eu/post/2018_newphdpublication/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I can now happily announce that the first chapter of my PhD has been accepted and is going to be published in the Journal &lt;a href=&#34;https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/16000587&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Ecography&lt;/a&gt;. In this piece I investigated whether pairwise compositional differences between species assemblages (so in the identity and amount of species found in a given place and time) can be explained by a dissimilarity in remotely-sensed vegetation index. &lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I furthermore found that past dissimilarities in photosynthetic activity improved the overall fit relative to current dissimilarities, therefore hinting at a &lt;em&gt;lag-effect&lt;/em&gt; that can be investigated via remote sensing. Also quite cool is that we use - to my knowledge for the first time - the same dissimilarity metric (the &lt;strong&gt;Bray-Curtis&lt;/strong&gt; index) to quantify both differences between species assemblages and entire remotely-sensed time series of photosynthetic activity.
Terminology and writeup took quite a while for this piece, so I am quite happy that it is finally out.
\&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
