<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Remote-sensing on Martin Jung - Environmental and data scientist</title>
    <link>http://martin-jung.github.io/tags/remote-sensing/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Remote-sensing on Martin Jung - Environmental and data scientist</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <copyright>Martin Jung 2017-2018 &amp;bull; &lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/&#34;&gt;&lt;i class=&#34;fa fa-cc&#34; aria-hidden=&#34;true&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 03 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://martin-jung.github.io/tags/remote-sensing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Local species assemblages are influenced more by past than current dissimilarities in photosynthetic activity</title>
      <link>http://martin-jung.github.io/publication/2018_jungpairwisedifferences/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://martin-jung.github.io/publication/2018_jungpairwisedifferences/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New PhD paper - Pairwise differences in photosynthetic activity</title>
      <link>http://martin-jung.github.io/post/2018_newphdpublication/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://martin-jung.github.io/post/2018_newphdpublication/</guid>
      <description>I can now happily announce that the first chapter of my PhD has been accepted and is going to be published in the Journal Ecography. In this piece I investigated whether pairwise compositional differences between species assemblages (so in the identity and amount of species found in a given place and time) can be explained by a dissimilarity in remotely-sensed vegetation index. I furthermore found that past dissimilarities in photosynthetic activity improved the overall fit relative to current dissimilarities, therefore hinting at a lag-effect that can be investigated via remote sensing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to Google Earth Engine</title>
      <link>http://martin-jung.github.io/post/2018_googleearthengine-intro/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://martin-jung.github.io/post/2018_googleearthengine-intro/</guid>
      <description>In a previous post, I gave a brief introduction how to use google cloud compute to kickstart your cloud computing experience. While it is possible to run large spatial operations on google cloud compute, it is quite time-consuming to set up all the routines to load and process geospatial data. Luckily there is now a new platform (currently in beta-testing) called Google Earth Engine (GEE) described as planetary scale platform for spatial analyses.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PhD research image prize</title>
      <link>http://martin-jung.github.io/post/2018-phd-poster-prize/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://martin-jung.github.io/post/2018-phd-poster-prize/</guid>
      <description>I won a prize :-) In this years Festival of Doctoral research at the University of Sussex I won the runner-up prize for the best image describing one&amp;rsquo;s doctoral research. The task was to submit a single image and 300 word abstract that visualizes and describes the goals of a persons doctoral research.
Picture seen above (click here for larger version). Here is the accompanying description:
Title: Going back in time with satellites to assist biodiversity conservation  In my PhD I investigate how past land changes continue to affect local biodiversity.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>